# Adrian Bavister

Location: **Uptown Dallas, Texas**Telephone: **972-854-2153**E-mail: **adrian@bavanco.co.uk** 

### **Personal Profile**

I am a technically minded, well organized engineer with an interest in everything computer based. I currently own a business where I offer my services as a website developer. This role has involved working on a range of design challenges utilizing my knowledge of various web languages.

I started my career in the field of digital electronics before my hobby of computing expanded into my full time job. Since then I have obtained computing qualifications and gained six years of valuable IT experience. I left London, England just under two years ago to marry and live in the United States on a permanent basis.

### **Career History**

Each role has offered a very different challenge which has expanded my skill set along the way.

### **Website Developer -** Sole Proprietorship

October 2011 to Present Day

- The bulk of my work as a website developer has involved the design and development of a custom web portal
  and underlying infrastructure to allow the client remote access to a vast range of instrumentation and controls
  relating to their latest range of industrial equipment.
- I am experienced at writing clean, standards based HTML, CSS and JavaScript or jQuery. I am proficient at Adobe Photoshop and have the ability to both conceive basic designs and to follow a customers specification.
- Most projects have relied heavily on server side scripting for which I have implemented designs using PHP or Python. I have experience with unit testing, working with revision control systems and implementing MySQL.
- I have good knowledge of using Ajax and JSON/XML data interchange formats.
- I am used to adhering to strict design standards and maintaining a high level of documentation.

#### **Customer Service Analyst** - NTT Communications, UK

January 2010 to July 2011

- My main duty was to be the first point of contact for customers using NTT's hosting services. I was required to offer friendly technical support via telephone, email and the online ticketing system.
- The scope of my support covered Windows and Linux based operating systems on desktops and servers as well as the configuration and support of any network devices the customer chose to use.
- I was responsible for managing, where appropriate, escalations to other support teams, vendors or partners to ensure the prompt and satisfactory resolution of customer support cases.
- The role involved a variety of shift patterns including weekend and night work. The nature of providing 24/7 support required flexibility on my part, in the form of filling in for others at very short notice.

### **Data Center Operations Technician -** Rackspace IT Hosting, UK

March 2007 to July 2009

- Rackspace is a growing IT hosting company with over 10 thousand customer servers across its London data centers. It's a main concern is customer and employee satisfaction and strives to be one of the best customer service companies around.
- My role in the company was to assemble, install and maintain a variety of servers and network devices, working to minimize any possible downtime.

- Secondary tasks included cabling servers to a high standard, server upgrades and maintenance, visual inspection of all servers to prevent potential failures and dealing with various requests from other departments such as server reboots or backup tape restores.
- My increased responsibility has included leading my shift when required as well as running the data center by myself on occasion.

# **IT Qualifications**

In 2007, I studied for and obtained the following qualifications:

- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)
- Microsoft Windows 2003 Server (MCP)
- Microsoft Windows XP (MCP)

### **Education**

I was educated in England, obtaining a Bachelor of Engineering Honors degree in Electronic Engineering from De Montfort University. I graduated in June 2000.

## **Additional Employment History**

After obtaining my degree in 2000, I worked as an Electronic Design Engineer for three companies before making the move to an IT based career in 2007. Below is a summary of my main roles and requirements:

- Design and development of electronic circuitry and hardware.
- Coding of fully functioning firmware for logic chips and the design and optimization of assembler code to be run on Digital Signal Processors and micro controllers.
- The ability to work unsupervised on complicated designs.
- Often there would be multiple projects running simultaneously requiring the ability to organize and prioritize workloads while working to strict deadlines.
- Fault finding and problem solving skills had to be impeccable as designs were tested on expensive hardware.
- Good communication skills were required to liaise with colleges and to explain the current technical situation to the management during meetings.
- Written communication skills were also very important as detailed technical documents had to be produced for my designs.

### **Interests and Hobbies**

- I have always had a natural ability to build and fix computers. I frequently help out all my family and friends with computer and network related problems.
- In my free time I design and maintain a hand full of websites for myself, my friends and my family. I recently
  created <a href="http://webdesign.bavanco.co.uk">http://webdesign.bavanco.co.uk</a> while my personal site <a href="http://www.bavanco.co.uk">http://www.bavanco.co.uk</a> has been active for
  eleven years.
- I enjoy traveling, live music and am an avid photographer.
- My wife and I are keen snorkelers.

#### References

Available upon request.